Timothy Panek

User Experience Designer

	Randolph,	NJ 07869
--	-----------	----------

973-517-1378

□ tpanek05@gmail.com

www.timothypanek.com

in linkedin.com/in/timothypanek

UX designer with 1 year of experience in crafting creative solutions to meet users' needs. Former professional counselor with 15 years of experience in understanding clients' unique struggles to help them overcome adversity and improve their quality of life. Passionate about making life easier for people through user-centered design.

Experience

Collaborative Support Programs of NJ Support Services, Clifton, NJ

12/2017 - Present Clinical Team Leader

- Supervise, manage, and direct Support Services staff in the performance of their daily duties. Develop solutions to client problems, ensuring staff provides simple and effective interventions while prioritizing client safety and wellness.
- Assess 100+ clients diagnosed with serious mental health conditions to identify personal challenges, pain points, and goals.
 Develop individualized plans used to address each identified need resulting in improved daily functioning and overall quality of life.
- Developed multiple tracking tools used by staff members agencywide to provide them with an easier way to track their daily, weekly, and monthly billable time as well as vital caseload information.
- Collaborate with team members and key stakeholders to provide superior services consistent with the client's identified needs.

Saint Clare's Health 2/2011 - 12/2017 L.E.A.R.N. of Northern NJ, Denville, NJ Clinician, Education Specialist

- Performed client-centered counseling focused on individuals' personal challenges, frustrations, and problems, facilitating movement toward goal achievement
- Identified inefficiencies in the program's process of collecting and organizing team statistics. Developed and maintained a simplified, efficient process to gather and interpret program data resulting in team members spending less time on reporting and more time on providing services to clients, increasing billable units of service.
- Established positive relationships with post-secondary institutions and treatment facilities to collaborate with community stakeholders, increasing the number of program referrals

Saint Clare's Health Transitions Program, Cedar Knolls, NJ

11/2005 - 2/2011 Counselor

- Provided case management and crisis intervention for clients with severe diagnoses, understanding their needs and facilitating treatment to help them regain independence.
- Created and facilitated group curriculum to address clients'
 readiness to re-enter the workforce, addressing client frustrations
 and fears. As a result, clients found the transition to work to be
 possible and positive, increasing intrinsic motivation.

UX Skills

User-Centered Design
Emotional & Visual Design
Mobile-First Design
Responsive Design
Competitive Analysis
User Research
Affinity Mapping
User Personas
User Stories
User Journeys
Information Architecture
Iterative Wireframing
Prototyping
Usability Testing
Preference Testing

Tools

Sketch InVision Balsamiq Usability Hub Microsoft Office

Education

Advanced UX Design Certification CareerFoundry, 2020

- UX Immersion
- UI for UX Designers Specialization
- Front End Web Development Specialization

MS, Health Care Management College of Saint Elizabeth, 2015

MA, Counseling

Fairleigh Dickinson University, 2010

BS, Psychology

Lindenwood University, 2005